Guide to the Edwin Clarke Gregory Papers, 1877-1948 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Edwin Clarke Gregory papers 1877-1948 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Gregory, Edwin Clarke, 1876-
2.8 linear feet Extent: 3,699 Items
Lawyer and North Carolina legislator, from Salisbury (Rowan Co.), North Carolina. Papers, primarily legal, business, and political correspondence, of Gregory and of his father-in-law, Lee Slater Overman, lawyer and U.S. Senator from North Carolina. Gregory's papers give much information on his career in the North Carolina Senate and relate to such topics as agriculture, gold mining, public aid, and public libraries. A majority of the papers before 1930 pertain to Overman's service in the U.S. Senate (1903-1930) and refer to such events as the North Carolina senatorial contest of 1902, the Espionage Acts of 1914 and 1915, and Alfred E. Smith's 1928 presidential campaign in North Carolina. Includes letters of Margaret Overman Gregory relating to her activities in charitable foundations and the American Red Cross about the time of World War I. Correspondents include Josiah W. Bailey, Josephus Daniels, Frank P. Graham, and Sam Rayburn.
RL.00505
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Edwin Clarke Gregory Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1956.
Biographical Note
Edwin Clarke Gregory was a lawyer and North Carolina legislator, from Salisbury (Rowan Co.), North Carolina.
Collection Overview
Papers, primarily legal, business, and political correspondence, of Gregory and of his father-in-law, Lee Slater Overman, lawyer and U.S. Senator from North Carolina. Gregory's papers give much information on his career in the North Carolina Senate and relate to such topics as agriculture, gold mining, public aid, and public libraries. A majority of the papers before 1930 pertain to Overman's service in the U.S. Senate (1903-1930) and refer to such events as the North Carolina senatorial contest of 1902, the Espionage Acts of 1914 and 1915, and Alfred E. Smith's 1928 presidential campaign in North Carolina. Includes letters of Margaret Overman Gregory relating to her activities in charitable foundations and the American Red Cross about the time of World War I. Correspondents include Josiah W. Bailey, Josephus Daniels, Frank P. Graham, and Sam Rayburn.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Bailey, Josiah William, 1873-1946; Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948; Graham, Frank Porter, 1886-1972; Rayburn, Sam, 1882-1961; Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944; American Red Cross; North Carolina. General Assembly -- Elections; United States. Congress -- Elections; Agriculture -- North Carolina; Espionage -- Law and legislation -- United States; Gold mines and mining -- North Carolina; Lawyers -- North Carolina; Legislators -- North Carolina -- Correspondence; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1928; Politicians' spouses -- North Carolina; Public libraries -- North Carolina; North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1953
Contents of Collection
- Edwin Clarke Gregory Papers, 1877-1948 and undated, (7 boxes)
  Collection includes correspondence as well as legal and financial papers.
  - Correspondence, 1897-1903 Jan. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1903 Feb.-1928 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1929-1939 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1948 and undated (Box 4)
  - Legal Papers, 1890-1948 and undated (Box 5)
  - Financial Papers, c. 1900-1920 and undated (Box 5)
  - Financial Papers, c. 1930-1940 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1877-1939 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1940-1948 and undated (Box 7)